TODD G. OLSEN

Phone: 253-258-4413 ~ Email: toddgolsen@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

To find a position with a well-established organization that can utilize my 21 years of professional experience and goal-oriented track record of consistently meeting and exceeding established goals and objectives related to management, training and education, and client relations.

EDUCATION

Highline Community College, Des Moines, WA

Graduated 2012

■ AAS – Network Specialist

2012

• Certificates: Network Skills, LAN, UNIX/Linux, Operating System Fundamentals

2012

■ Intern: Highline Community College, Wired Telecommunications Services

Washington State University, Pullman WA

Graduated 2001

- Major: Bachelors in Humanities Emphasis: Graphic Design
- Minor: Communications
- Intern: Technical Manager for Holland Library

CERTIFICATES

Operating System Fundamentals, LAN, UNIX/Linux, Network Skills, Incident Command System, ICS for Single Resources and Initial Action Requirements, National Incident Management System (NIMS), And National Response Framework.

RELATED WORK EXPERIENCE

Paracom, Inc.

October 2018 ~ March 2020

IT Manager

- Developed and designed the back end Clover system for three restaurant's at the airport with an average of 100 transactions per hour
- Developed a UPC-A Barcode system for all internal products to be printed and scanned for inventory
- Oversaw the new construction of a restaurant and the installation of the network
- Supplied support for 200+ employees
- Analyzed network traffic and made decisions about network security
- Updated website as needed and worked with the graphics department to redesign
- Kept a detailed inventory log of all IT related items
- Set up of new computers and laptops for all staff

Steeler, Inc.

August 2012 ~ February 2018

IT Manager

- Active Directory
- Administer desktop computers, printers, software deployment, security updates and patches
- Experience with backups and restores to disk and tape library
- Experienced with security software, virus detection and anti-spam prevention
- Hardware and software installation, maintenance, and troubleshooting
- Experienced Remote desktop, VPN using SonicWall
- Maintained and enhanced all desktops, laptop computers and mobile phones
- Provided backup and data recovery services
- Web camera installation and support
- Server Installs and Maintenance
- Supported storage area network
- Maintained and expended network LAN and WAN connectivity through routers, switches, firewalls, and wireless access points at Corporate and 14 branch locations throughout the western United States.
- Maintained Businesses Intranet Site

Technical Manager

- Maintained current web content for library website, provided quality assurance on staff submitted web content and transferring existing content into a new content management system
- Assisted students and staff with questions pertaining to computer related issues within library system
- Effectively collaborate with non-technical people to interpret the information needs and issues in order to troubleshoot errors

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Operating Systems: Windows XP, 7, and 10 Professional, Windows Server 2003/2008(R2)/2012(R2) and 2016. Exchange Server 2013/2016, WSUS, Terminal Server

Hardware: Switches, Hubs, Laptops & Workstations, Hard Drives, Processors, Power Supplies, CD/DVD Writers, Mother Boards, Modems, Network Cards, Memory, Printers, Scanners and other peripherals

Software: Milestone, Backup Exec, GoToMeeting, Avaya, Hyper-V, VirtualBox, Windows Terminal Server, McAfee, Norton, MS Office 2010/2013/2016, Acrobat, Adobe CS6,

Networks/Protocols: LAN/WAN, TCP/IP, POP3

VOLUNTEER WORK

King County Office of Emergency Management – Support Team (Provide Technical Support with WebEOC, Audio Visual System, and computer Login Process), Black Box Communications (Set up of Phones, Ethernet lines and installation of Network)

OVER-VIEW

Set up computers and in house networks, 3 years networking field experience, 8 years of technical experience, 8 years in sales and marketing, and 22 years of customer service

SKILLS

- Network Organization
- Computer Hardware and Software installation
- Virtualization
- Interviewing and Management
- Customer Service
- Excellent People Skills
- Presentations and Negotiating
- Technical Experience

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Golf Savings Bank
Loan Officer

February 2009 ~ March 2010
Puyallup, WA

Ricoh Business Solutions

January 2008 ~ September 2008

Senior Account Executive

Sellevue, WA

Lehman BrothersApril 2003 ~ April 2007Account Executive / 100% CommissionSan Diego, CA

Accredited Home Lenders

Account Executive / Underwriter

March 2002 ~ March 2003

San Diego, CA

REFERENCES

Available Upon Request